James Gross NLRB Files /4057
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series II. NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS BOARD (OLD) 1934-1935 (JULY)
  - Sub-Series A. NATIONAL LABOR RELATIONS BOARD RECORDS
    - Sub-Series 2. CORRESPONDENCE 6/5/34-7/6/35
      - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 33)
        11/4/34-11/30/34; Letter from Henry L. McCarthy (Region 10) to Millis in regard to Dean Spencer and Sec.7a; Millis' reply; from Millis to Milton Handler (Professor, The Law School, Columbia University) about his resignation; confidential memo from Millis on the operating expenses of the NLRB; Handler's resignation; Executive Order no.6905, appointment of a chairman to the NLRB, etc.; memo concerning Sec.2 of Executive Order no. 6905, (limiting the power of the NLRB); from Blackwell Smith (Acting General Counsel, NRA) to Edwin S. Smith about Board preview and approval of industrial relations boards; from Millis and Smith to R. Gordon Wagenet concerning unanimous action; Edwin S. Smith's and Franklin W. Wolf's (Assistant Deputy Administrator, Div.no.7, FWW, NRA)discussion of a modification of Sec.7 of Article II; from Frances Perkins to Francis Biddle (Chairman, NLRB) concerning problems with labor relations and compliance in the textile industry; Millis' discussion of the Textile Board; letter from Frank E. Coffee (Director, Region 6) to Benedict Wolf about the cotton textile strike, (Standard-Coosa-Thatcher Mills); from W.H. Davis to Sol A. Rosenblatt on the Textile Labor Relations Board; memo regarding the conference between Perkins, Millis, Walter P.(Judge) Stacy (Chairman Textile Labor Relations Board), William H. David(s?) concerning the NLRB/Textile Labor Relations Board Relationship; Sidney Hillman's (President, Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America) discussion of Donald Richberg and Sec.7a; from W.J. Voss to Edwin S. Smith on the NLRB's agreement with the NRA Compliance Div.; from Franklin Wolf to Edwin S. Smith confirming a change in the Photo-Engraving Board; from Herber Blankenhorn to Francis Biddle concerning the Newspaper Guild Cases (the Burgess case), and the discharge of Guild Chapter officers; from Edwin S. Smith to Biddle on industrial boards, includes results of 10/2/34 questionnaire; letter from Biddle to Walter (Judge) Stacy providing assistance in the textile mill cases.
      - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 34)
        12/3/34-12/14/34; Outline, "notes on proposed legislation"; significant correspondence on San Francisco Call-Bulletin and Dean S. Jennings case (Newspaper Guild) among Francis Biddle, Herber Blankenhorn, Donald Richberg (Executive Director, National Emergency Council), Blackwell Smith and the President (subjects discussed include the code of fair competition, "infiltration" of the labor movement, and government agencies working at cross purposes); to Golden W. Bell (Dept. of Justice) from Thomas I. Emerson (Attorney, NLRB) and Calvert Magruder on the Guide Lamp Corp. case; from Blankenhorn to Biddle about elections, with attached notice of Los Angeles Regional Labor Board sponsored election at Proctor and Gamble, includes a list of facts to be used by regional boards to develop hearings dated 7/31/34, tables on the number of employees elgible to vote dated 1/10/35-6/16/35, tables on the number of units won by type of organization dated 1/35-6/35; correspondence between the President, the Attorney General, and the Board concerning uncoded industries, NLRB jurisdiction, and a conference on uncoded industries; from A.J. Altmeyer (Second Assistant Secretary, Dept. of Labor) to Biddle, Millis, and Edwin S. Smith in regard to furture legislation; Biddle's reply.
      - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 35)
        12/15/34-12/31/34; Memo on the budget with reference to Executive Orders numbers 6548, and 6550; Harold M. Stephen's and Francis Biddle's request that a bill of complaint be filed in the Guide Lamp Corporation case; from Harry Millis to R. Gordon Wagenet about redrafting Wagner's Industrial Disputes Bill; Benedict Wolf's meeting with the St. Louis Regional Labor Board, includes analysis of Garvey (Regional Director), and the need for improved enforcement; from Magruder to Biddle about back pay; from Beatrice Stern to Wagenet concerning San Francisco Barge Strike - Jestlyn Mfg. Co.; from Louis Howe (Secretary to the President) to Francis Biddle in regard to an Executive Order; from C.M. Baker (First Vice President, International Typographical Union) to Biddle in regard to the New Orleans Typographical Union no. 17 versus the New Orleans Item-Tribune, asking the Board to direct the Newspaper Industrial Board (which has nearly established a policy of deadlocking) (4pp); Baker's request for a Board supervised election, attached is a 7 page memo outlining steps taken toward securing an election; from Bill Davy (Cleveland Newspaper Guild) to Biddle congratulating him on the San Francisco Call-Bulletin versus Dean Jennings decision; from Edwin S. Smith to Frances Perkins about missing an important meeting; from Biddle to Perkins with unattached draft of Wagner Bill; from Biddle suggesting the deadlock involving the Newspaper Industrial Board be broken by the appointment of an impartial panel member; letter from P.G. (Philip G.?) Phillips to Biddle about the Wagner Bill, includes a reference to Lloyd Garrison's telegram; letter from Biddle to Perkins in regard to the Executive Order of 11/15/34, Sec.2 (budgetary control), includes mention of a fundamental difference of opinion about the NLRB and its purpose; telegram from Lloyd Garrison to Biddle recommending the Wagner Bill be read in its original form (remove the mediation clause); Biddle's reply, includes a 7 point discussion of the Wagner Bill, and a reference to Perkins as "her Ladyship"; from Francis Biddle to the President opposing tight budgetary control of the Board by the Dept. of Labor; from Biddle to Edwin S. Smith concerning his future meeting with Louis Howe; from Biddle to the Attorney General about filing the bill of equity in the Guide Lamp Corp. case.
      - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 36)
        Undated (1934); Memo of the proposed Wagner Bill; a Dept. of Labor list of Textile Labor Relations Board members; 10 point position paper from an unknown author on Board status and the proposed Wagner Bill, gives special attention to Sections 6b, 8 and 9 (6pp); from Benedict Wolf to the Board about his meeting with the Fort Worth Regional Labor Board, includes a discussion of needed improvements in Sec.7a, the preparation of complaints for unions, and praise for Dr. Elliott (Director).
      - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 37)
        1/2/35-1/28/35; Letter from Edwin S. Smith to Louis Howe (says '34) on the relationship between the NLRB and the Newspaper Industrial Board; from Harry Millis to Biddle on the Item-Tribune Publishing Co. case and labor's handling of it; from Robert Watts to Alice Rossiter on the Pacific Gas and Electric case; from Beatrice Stern to Gordon Wagenet on the mediation of strikes; 5 point memo from Nathan Witt (Assistant General Counsel, NLRB) to Biddle on the Wagner Bill, points include: closed shop, arbitration, representation before the Board, judicial enforcement and review, unfair labor practices, and the removal or modification of Sec.12; 10 point memo from Biddle on the Wagner Bill; detailed memo from Edwin S. Smith to Biddle and Millis on suggested discussion of industrial boards for inclusion in the Sixth Monthly Report to the President, specific subjects include Board handling of Sec. 7a cases, and policy and procedure; from Edwin S. Smith to Biddle and Millis about his meeting with Louis Howe, particularly a proposed policy on Sec.7a cases originally heard by industrial boards; from Edwin S. Smith to Louis Howe, with attached statement of NLRB policy on jurisdiction in Sec 7a cases with respect to industrial boards; from Edwin S. Smith to Biddle with revisions in the Sixth Monthly Report to the President; from Biddle to Perkins and Howe forwarding correspondence between Biddle and Harvey J. Kelly (Chairman, Newspaper Industrial Board) regarding the Newspaper Industrial Boards' ineffectiveness in handling Sec.7a cases; proposed statement by NLRB defining its jurisdiction; from Biddle to Richberg about the Boards' proposed statement of jurisdiction; from the President to Biddle setting down rules to guide the Board in situations affecting special codes, rule 3 addresses the problem of interpreting Sec.7a; from Biddle to the President about the limitations imposed on him by Executive Order of 11/15/34, concerns the issues of strick budgetary control, and sole control of hiring and discharging employees; from Francis Biddle to Perkins on the proposed statement of jurisdiction; report from Mr. Crawford of the "Philadelphia Record" to Biddle relating to the Jennings case; significant memo from Biddle to the Board on his talk with the President, about the Executive Order of 11/15/34; letter of resignation from Edwin S. Smith to the President; from Biddle (?) to the Board summarizing his meeting with the President, topics discussed include the handling of Sec.7a cases, the Jennings case and the resignations of Harry Millis and Edwin S. Smith; from Biddle to Edwin S. Smith asking him to prepare a report on the Newspaper situation; from Millis to Gordon Wagenet assuring him the Board will continue to operate; from the President to Biddle requesting information on the Newspaper Industrial Board, particularly cases involving violations of Sec.7a; memo from Herber Blankenhorn to the Board explaining why joint boards are inherently unfitted to handle Sec.7a cases.
      - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 38)
        2/1/35-2/28/35; Correspondence between the President and Francis Biddle concerning the report on the Newspaper Industrial Board; 5 telegrams and letters on the possible appointments of Malcolm Ross and Harold P. Voss to the Board; from Stanley Mathewson to Biddle about problems with panel members (4pp); Harold M. Stephens' (Assistant Attorney General) and Biddle's discussion of the Dresner and Son case, the Guide Lamp Corp. case, and due process; from H.K. Brunck to Biddle on the meeting of the Newspaper Board with attached summary; from Biddle to Elinore Herrick informing her that Benedict Wolf is coming to New York to set-up a system that will improve the current one; Perkins' and Biddle's discussion of staff investigators, and the lack of power to issue subpoenas; from Biddle to John J. Kane (Pressmen's Union) concerning a change in the directorship of the Pittsburgh Regional Board; from Philip G. Phillips and Philip Levy to the Board on the final draft of the Wagner Bill; from Marion Smith (Chairwoman, Region 6) to Biddle concerning Preston S. Arkwright, and the Board as a permanent organization; 4 memos from Wolf to Herrick on complaints, the reception room, mediation, and hearings; from Stephen Early to McIntyre about expediting appointments to the Board; significant letter from the Attorney General to Biddle in response to Biddle's letter to Assistant Attorney General Stephens of 2/12/35, includes discussion of majority-rule cases, cases of interference with self-organization, discriminatory cases, interstate commerce cases, cases against regional boards, Blue Eagle cases, and election cases; from Charlton Ogburn (attorney) to Stephen Early regarding Harry Millis' resignation.
      - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 39)
        3/1/35-3/30/35; Memo from Edwin S. Smith to Biddle about the Procter and Gamble Manufacturing opinion, with attention to the issue of an exclusive bargaining agent; Biddle's and regional board members' discussion of support for and oppostion to the Wagner Bill among employers; from Edwin S. Smith to Paul Herzog (Assistant to the General Counsel) opposing the Houde Engineering Corp. decision, and discussing discriminatory discharge and restitution; from William Leiserson (Chairman, National Mediation Board) to Biddle with attached chart of procedures under the Railway Labor Act for handling collective bargaining cases; Biddle's summary of his meeting with the Pittsburgh Regional Labor Board including his request for Jewett's resignation, and his description of board members Ladd and Blackmore as "reactionary"; outline from Biddle to Regional Labor Boards on the procedure to be followed in handling election petitions; Edwin S. Smith's and Ralph Lind's discussion of the Houde Engineering Corp. cases and "immediate reinstatement of the complainant"; from Wolf to the Board regarding the New York Regional Board, suggesting changes in procedure and discussing personnel (he mentions Herrick "has no particular respect for the NLRB"); from the White House about Millis' resignation; from Thomas I. Emerson (Attorney) to Biddle on cases pending in the Dept. of Justice, and testimony before the Senate Committee on the breakdown in enforcement of Sec.7a (8pp); from Francis Biddle to the President discussing the report on industrial boards; Biddle to the President with attached report on the Newspaper Industrial Board (8pp); from Biddle to Perkins discussing the ineffectiveness of regional boards; from Towne Nylander to R.C. Jacobson (Director, Region 15) on rules of conduct for hearings; from Biddle to Herrick and Golden on reorganization of their regional boards; report on the "Substance of John L. Lewis' Remarks", contains the notion that men of labor can not understand labor; from Millis to Jacobson saying he was "trapped into remaining on the Board"; from Philip Levy to Calvert Magruder in regard to the Wagner Bill, the issue of majority-rule, and a reference to the cross-examination of Magruder by Walsh; from Emerson to Edwin S. Smith on the Appeal by Union from Decisions of Textile Labor Relations Board in the Ninety-Six Cotton Mill and Alexander Manufacturing Company; to the Editor of the "New York Herald Tribune" refuting in detail, point by point Walter Lippman's editorial of 3/28/35.
      - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 40)
        4/1/35-4/29/35; Letter from Calvert Magruder (General Counsel, NLRB) to T.J. McGreevy about the Houde Engineering Corp. case; from Magruder to W.W. Britton (President, Metal Polishers International Union) on the Guide Lamp case; Francis Biddle's and Isador Lubin's (Commissioner of Labor Statistics) discussion of the report on activities of industrial relations boards; correspondence relating to the Wagner Bill includes: a letter from Leon H. Keyserling (Clerk, Committee on Public Lands and Surveys) to Biddle, attached is Wagner's rebuttal to Walter Lippmann`s editorial, detailed memos from Philip Levy to Magruder on the Davis Amendment and Walter Gordon Merritt's amendments, a letter from Roger N. Baldwin (Director, American Civil Liberties Union) to Biddle opposing government intervention in labor disputes, attached is a letter co-authored by Baldwin and Arthur Garfield Hays to Wagner dated 3/30/35 spelling out defects in the Bill; from Mathewson to Biddle on employer opposition, with an attached clipping "The Labor Board Bill" from the Cincinnati Post, and 2 memos for Senator Walsh focusing on miscellaneous amendments, and the civil service status of employees; from George S. Wheeler to Edwin S. Smith on election results; from Millis to the Board on his trip to the Middle West (6pp); from Biddle to the Board on the Indianapolis Regional Board; from Levy to Magruder on the separation of the functions of judge and prosecutor; from Biddle to Professor William H. Spenser (School of Business, University of Chicago) discussing his pamphlet on collective bargaining and an employers' duty.
      - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 41)
        5/4/35-5/31/35; Letter from Francis Biddle to the Attorney General in regard to pending cases (Trinity Portland Cement Co.,) Guide Lamp case, General Printing Co. case; from Biddle to William P. Connery, Jr. (Congressman) discussing the following issues: H.R.7979, and the National Labor Relations Bill, and the idea of the Board as an independent agency; from Thomas I. Emerson to the Board about a report on litigation involving Sec.7a; from Biddle to Benedict Wolf, Beatrice Stern and Paul Herzog asking them to prepare an agenda for a meeting considering personnel, budget, and the function of panels; from Levy to Magruder on the Labor Disputes Bill; annotated memo to the Board on the organization of regional boards, includes 24 individual memos, one on each board, evaluating its personnel and giving salary information (26pp); from the Administrative Staff to the Board on procedure which might be followed under the Wagner Bill (8pp); from the Administrative Staff to the Board sketching the organizational set-up of the new National Labor Relations Board; from the Administrative Staff to the Board on the organization of regional boards; from Biddle to regional boards with a table showing 3629 cases handled by regional boards since 10/35; from Benedict Wolf to the United Automobile Workers Federal Union, no.18839 concerning the Houde Engineering Corp. case.
      - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 42)
        6/1/35-6/29/35; Memo from Philip Levy to Calvert Magruder listing independent establishments under the Federal Budget for the fiscal year 1936; personal letter from Charlton Ogburn to Francis Biddle giving a legal analysis of a substitute N.R.A. (prima facie evidence); from Elias Lieberman (attorney) to Biddle with an outline, "Plan for Uniform Essential Labor Standards Throughout the Nation," intended purpose of which is to salvage the labor standards secured by the N.R.A.; from Benedict Wolf to Regional Board No.1 telling it to close pending cases since all codes of fair competition have been declared invalid; from Biddle to Harold M. (Judge) Stephens in regard to Blue Eagle cases, and "vacating" decisions; telegram from the NLRB to Regional Board No.16 telling it to send all records; from Edwin S. Smith to Gordon Wagenet about the status of the Wagner Bill, and an arrangement with the Division of Conciliation; from Edwin S. Smith to Magruder assigning projects to the legal staff; from Harry Millis (Professor, Dept. of Economics, University of Chicago) to the President discussing the Wagner-Connery Industrial Disputes Bill, and recommending Francis Biddle and Edwin S. Smith to the new NLRB, as well as a conservative; from Herber Blankenhorn to the Board with advice on legal approaches and a discussion of test cases (like Houde) and marginal cases; from Biddle discussing regional and national board personnel with attention to Dorothea de Schweinitz and Elinore Herrick; legal memo to the General Counsel presenting "a short resume of the extent to which the judiciary has controlled administrative bodies as to form of complaints and findings of fact".
      - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 43)
        7/1/35-7/6/35; Letter from A.J. Altmeyer (Second Assistant Secretary, Dept. of Labor) to Marvin McIntyre, with attached statement defining the National Labor Relations Act (NLRA), and the text of the President's statement on signing the NLRA dated 7/5/35; from Francis Biddle to Lloyd Garrison requesting a recommendation for Harold A. Cranefield; Garrison's recommendation, as well as advice on others to fill Board positions (Walter Fisher and William H. Davis); from the NLRB to Regional Board No.16 announcing that the NLRA became effective 7/5/35, and telling them to continue to mediate special class disputes.
    - Sub-Series 3. REPORTS AND OFFICIAL DOCUMENTS 6/34-8/35
      - Statement issued by the President upon the signing of an executive order creating the National Labor Relations Board., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 44)
        Jun-34
      - NLRB report of seventy-seven cases left unfinished by the NLB., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 45)
        Jul-34
      - Report to the President by the NLRB, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 46)
        8/34; for the period 7/9/34-8/9/34, inclusive. Submitted through the Secretary of Labor pursuant to Sec.4, Sub-Sec.2d of Executive Order no.6763.
      - NLRB release (143), the Guide Lamp Corporation decision., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 47)
        Sep-34
      - Reports, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 48)
        10/34; Report to the President by the NLRB for the Period 9/10/34-10/9/34, inclusive; Regional Labor Board: comparative analysis of annual payrolls as of 6/30/34 and 10/31/34; Functions of the National Labor Relations Board and the Regional Labor Boards and Their Relations to Other Boards and Agencies of Government.
      - Reports, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 49)
        11/34; Report to the President by the NLRB for the period 10/10/34-11/9/34, inclusive; address by Edwin S. Smith, member NLRB, before New England Conference, Boston; address by Dr. Billikoph, Philadelphia Boards First Anniversary luncheon.
      - Reports, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 50)
        12/34; Report to the President by the NLRB for the period 11/10/34-12/9/34, inclusive; NLRB's statement on the San Francisco Call-Bulletin case; the (Wagner) Labor Disputes Act (S.2926); release for morinig papers, a letter from the New York office of the American Newspaper Guild to Donald R. Richberg.
      - Reports, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 51)
        1/35; Report to the President by the NLRB for the period 12/10/34-1/9/35, inclusive; elections to determine employee representation conducted by the NLRB and the Regional Labor Relations Boards, 7/10/34-1/9/35, by George Shaw Wheeler; conference called by the Newspaper Industrial Board.
      - Reports, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 52)
        2/35; Report to the President by the NLRB for the period 1/10/35-2/9/35, inclusive; report of the special committee on the Government and Labor of the Twentieth Century Fund, Inc.; report to the NLRB on an inquiry into industrial relations boards; press release for date of Mr. Davis' appearance before Senate Hearing.
      - Reports, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 53)
        3/35; Report to the President by the NLRB for the period 2/10/35-3/9/35, inclusive; address of Francis Biddle before the community forum at Carnegie Lecture Hall Pittsburgh, PA, and press release; "The Government and Collective Bargaining" by Sumner H. Slichter (Harvard Graduate School of Business Administration).
      - Reports, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 54)
        4/35; Report to the President by the NLRB for the period 3/10/35-4/9/35, inclusive; St. Louis address by Biddle.
      - Reports, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 55)
        5/35; Address by Vito Marcantonio before the Labor Committee; report on enforcement and the expansion of the legal staff; NLRB press release on the addition of panels to Regional Labor Board, Dist. 6 (Baltimore); NLRB press release, statement on stopping arguments and hearings.
      - Reports, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 56)
        6/35; Report to the Vice President for Region XIII to the Second Annual Convention of the American Newspaper Guild; report (84pp) to the NLRB on an inquiry into industrial labor relations boards with attached White House correspondence; elections to determine employee representation conducted by the NLRB and the Regional Labor Boards(7/15/34-6/16/35); elections conducted by the Regional Labor Boards during the period (1/10/35- 6/16/35); House of Representatives, 74th Congress, 1st session, report no.1371, NLRB conference report submitted by Mr. Connery (to accompany S.1958); Congressional Record, 10704, 10705, House, (S.1958); Congressional Record, 10668, Senate, settlement of labor disputes - conference report; resume of the extent to which the judiciary has controlled administrative bodies as to form of complaints and findings of facts by I.S. Dorfman.
      - Reports, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 57)
        7/35; Report to the President from the NLRB for the period; 7/9/34(5)-8/27/35, inclusive; the National Labor Relations Act - Legislative History by P.L. (Philip Levy).
      - Reports (Box 1, Folder 58)